<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Mental Belly Rubs]]></title><description><![CDATA[Cooks with hot fire. Codes with pure lighting. Writes like a sumo tango dancer. Eats ice cream with a little spoon. ]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 10:44:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Learning to type faster: Why?]]></title><description><![CDATA[We are going to begin a 30 day journey of 10 mins/day typing practice on keybr.com to see what happens!]]></description><link>https://calvinlang.io//posts/typing-why-learn/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://calvinlang.io//posts/typing-why-learn/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Why do I want to type faster?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be more productive.
I want to take notes with more fluidity. Less stop start, less “Wait what the heck did he just say?”
I will be able to write emails and code faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Questions going forward:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will typing practice improve my typing in either accuracy, speed, or both?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will typing practice improve my real world typing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will improving my typing improve my productivity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;We are going to make a bold assumption:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning to type faster will make me more productive&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;At the end we will ask 3 questions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is my note taking more fluid? Is there less pause/play of the video I’m watching?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I faster at getting out my ideas over email or my own journaling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I faster at coding? This probably the least likely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Current Typing Pain Points&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note taking is inefficient. I find myself frantically trying to get a thought down as the speaker has already moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time I make a mistake that the process of backspacing makes me lose track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brain like to jump around (ENFP you see) and I find I’m typing and my brain has already moved onto something else. I lose my place. Could faster typing help focus?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I am using the shift key and/or punctuation, I tend to need to reset my hands for a second. Sometimes I have to look down and double check where the ’ vs ” is. This loses momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hate when I type “SOmething” and then it’s like, backspace 8 times just to write the same word. It’s a real momentum killer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How will I do this?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I found a typing practice site. Some of them are visually quite unpleaant. I settled on using &lt;a href=&quot;www.keybr.com&quot;&gt;KeyBr&lt;/a&gt;. It’s free, clean interface, and quick to setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the part I liked the most about KeyBr was the setting to include capitals and punctuation on every word. This is the closest typing practice I’ve seen to code, yet soft enough that I feel it reflects typing a normal message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fcalvinlang%2FW6xvtzrDzo.png?alt=media&amp;#x26;token=32609bed-52cf-40d6-b429-c63d1a9a817e&quot;&gt;
Okay, pretty basic.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fcalvinlang%2Fv1Qn0CtYYW.png?alt=media&amp;#x26;token=978f7e90-17d9-4440-9199-28979af1be34&quot;&gt;
Look at all those capitals and punctuation! It’s like coding! There’s quotations, colons, semi-colons, questions marks, with lots and lot of periods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We are going to practice exactly 10 minutes a day for 30 days.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day One Complete! Not-impressive.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://firebasestorage.googleapis.com/v0/b/firescript-577a2.appspot.com/o/imgs%2Fapp%2Fcalvinlang%2Fhh5x-TInu8.png?alt=media&amp;#x26;token=5166db05-c928-4fd8-a801-fd2822471ddc&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pretty sad Calvin. Pretty sad.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gotta tell you, this first typing experience was pretty intense. Trying to focus 10 minutes straight with zero impulse, no scratching the nose, no sipping the water, no crying at my desk. The little counter taking count of every single mistake made was daunting. It was like trying to play a game but with more punishment than reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that I attribute my low score being in a new platform. There is going to be a learning curve to get used to. So mayyyybe we can add 10%… and round up. I don’t seriously type this slow do I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also keep in mind this includes a capitalization and punctuation on every single word. Most sentences you type in an email will never reflect this. I’m sure my typing speed would be higher with normal text. Onwards!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>